Subindex build by Linnet
Created time 16.01.10 01:10:59
He is so far from here...
他离这如此遥远
across the very mountain...
穿过山脉
I see him...
我看见他
I hear him...
我听见他
I feel him...
我感觉到他
and I feel him touching me.
我感觉到他对我的触摸
Mademoiselle,
the other classes have left already.
小姐 别的班已经离开了
Yes, we should go.
对 我们该走了
- Bilitis, where are you going?
- To go and change.
- 比莉婷丝 你去哪儿？
- 去换衣服
No, no, come as you are.
The others are waiting.
别别 穿这身走 别人在等
Okay.
好
Hooray for Ms. Larsen!
拉森小姐万岁！
To the beach!
去海滩！
- Without a bathing suit!
- Especially without a bathing suit!
- 没有泳衣！
- 没有泳衣更好！
Listen now, girls.
现在听着 姑娘们
It's too late to go to the abbey.
时间太晚了不能去修道院
I changed our plans,
but behave yourselves.
我改变了计划 但你们要表现好
Don't worry Ms. Larsen...
放心吧 拉森小姐
We always behave like ladies!
我们总是表现得像淑女！
Oh! It's cold!
哦 好冷！
We must hurry!
我们必须赶快！
Come, let's go!
来 我们走！
- Stay together!
- I want to bathe!
- 呆在一起！
- 我想洗个澡！
Stay with me!
跟我呆着！
You never do things with the others.
你从不跟别人一起做事
Are you still fighting?
你还在闹别扭？
Hey, look at these!
嗨 看这！
- I have them too!
- Mine is larger!
- 我也有！
- 我的更大！
I have something better!
我有更好的！
If I was in love, I would choose Flora.
如果我恋爱 我会选弗洛拉
Look at them! Disgusting!
看她们！令人作呕！
- I will never kiss a boy.
- Except when you're in love.
- 我绝不会吻一个男孩
- 除了你恋爱了
I'm not at all interested!
我根本不感兴趣
Girls, please...
姑娘们 拜托
Sit down.
坐下
Head up, back straight.
抬头挺胸
Show him to me.
把它给我看
He belongs to both of us, let's see!
它属于我们俩 给我看！
Mademoiselle.
小姐
Mademoiselle, yes, you.
小姐 没错 你
Head up, beautiful right...
抬头 美女 对...
Smile... attention...
笑...注意...
Thank you!
谢谢！
Okay, get your things ready.
好 去收拾好你们的东西
I looked at him cross-eyed,
then he took the picture.
我用斗鸡眼看他 然后他拍了照
He can't be that good a photographer.
He's too cute!
他不可能是个好摄影师 他太可爱了！
Why do we have to wrap up now?
We have so much to do tomorrow.
为什么我们现在必须收拾？
我们明天有好多事要做呢
Quiet, girls, quiet.
You are not on holiday.
安静 姑娘们 安静 你们还没放假
Girls...
姑娘们
together...
聚在一起...
size order...
按高矮顺序...
Very good. Head up.
很好 抬头
That's it!
就这样
- Are you coming to the festival tomorrow?
- Yes, certainly.
- 明天汇演你来吗？
- 当然来
- It's our class that's doing the show.
- Really?
- 由我们班演出节目
- 真的？
Don't move... that's good.
别动 很好
Smile...
笑...
Attention!
注意！
Thank you!
谢谢！
- What did he say?
- Nothing.
- 他说什么？
- 没什么
His name is Lucas
他叫卢卡斯
I let the turtle go.
我放了海龟
- Touch?
- Hey, are you crazy?
- 打到了！
- 嗨 你疯了吗？
Do you do that to all the boys?
你给所有男孩做这个？
No. You're the first to pass here.
不 你是第一个经过的
You could have hurt me, you know?
你本可能伤到我 你知道吗？
Oh, with a piece of bread.
哦 用一片面包
It's the intention that counts.
The attack was premeditated.
你有伤害意图 有攻击预谋
To you, I'm like a boy.
对你来说 我就像个男孩
You don't look like a boy.
你不像男孩
My father said I could have been a boy.
You'd better be careful.
我爸爸说我本可能是男孩 你最好小心
What name did your father give you?
你爸爸给你取什么名字？
Bilitis.
比莉婷丝
What are you doing?
你干什么？
I came to see if Bilitis is a boy.
我来看比莉婷丝是不是男孩
- If you come any closer, I'll shout.
- Go ahead.
- 你再靠近我就喊了
- 喊吧
I'll jump.
我会跳下去
Oh, you would jump for me?
哦 你会为我跳下去？
- What do you mean 'for me'?
- No, not for me, for you.
- 你什么意思“为我”？
- 不 不是为我 为你
- For you?
- Not for you, for Lucas.
- 为你？
- 不是为你 为卢卡斯
That's me.
就是我
I think you're crazy.
我觉得你疯了
Crazy about you.
为你而疯
Can I kiss you?
我能吻你吗？
Go ahead, I dare you to try.
吻呀 我谅你不敢
What is it?
怎么了？
He tried to kiss me.
他想吻我
Lucas tried to kiss you?
卢卡斯想吻你？
More or less.
多多少少
How, more or less?
怎么 多多少少？
I didn't want to.
我没愿意
Bilitis loves Lucas...
比莉婷丝爱卢卡斯...
When is your father coming?
什么时候你爸爸来？
In the next two or three weeks.
两三周后
After he returns from Canada.
等他从加拿大回来
Who is that woman,
who's taken you in?
那女人是谁？收容你住的？
A girlfriend of my father.
我爸爸一个女性朋友
Is she old?
她年纪很大了？
No, she's the daughter of
a friend of my father's.
不 她是我爸爸一个朋友的女儿
The last time I saw her,
I was still little.
上次我看见她我还小
Would you miss me?
你会想念我吗？
More or less.
多多少少
Who do you prefer, Lucas or me?
你更喜欢谁 卢卡斯还是我？
What's got into you?
你怎么了？
Close your eyes
闭上你的眼睛
I am Lucas.
我是卢卡斯
But no, you are a girl.
但你不是 你是个女孩
Quit it.
停止
Close your eyes.
闭上你的眼睛
It's important for our former
students to return later on.
我们之前的校友回来很重要
For the younger ones,
the example is inspiring for them.
是鼓舞年轻一辈学生的榜样
And for the elders...
Oh... Pardon me...
对于老一辈来说...抱歉...
It is pleasant to return one's
self to the "old" ambience.
回到老氛围也是乐事
The ambience today is quite exceptional.
今天的氛围非常特别
The students are excited by our festival.
学生们激动于我们的汇演
They aren't here on hand.
她们哪里还在上学
- It's like they are on holiday already.
- I know how it is.
- 就像她们已经放假了
- 我知道如何
Yes, but, Mr...
是的 但是先生...
Yes, I know that Melissa has
been well educated.
没错 我知道梅丽莎受到良好教育
That's the reason why I married her.
这就是为什么我娶她
I look awful
我看起来好糟
I look ugly.
我看起来好丑
You look like a clown.
你看起来像小丑
- And you a brush.
- You want a smack?
- 你是没人要
- 你想要一巴掌吗？
You are a reject.
你是次品
And to see my face!
来看我的脸！
- Well, you didn't smile.
- I moved!
- 你没有笑
- 我笑了！
What are you looking at?
That's the wrong side!
你在看哪里？方向错了！
- Lucas Mercier... photographer.
- Give me that!
- 卢卡斯・梅西耶...摄影师
- 给我！
Watch it. Do you want everyone to know?
小心 你想人人都知道吗？
- Know what?
- "Know what?"
- 知道什么？
- “知道什么”？
About you and Lucas!
你和卢卡斯的事！
Come and look!
来看啊！
- Who is that?
- Look at her, she's beautiful.
- 是谁？
- 看她 她好美
- And he's handsome!
- They don't look like parents.
- 他好英俊！
- 他们看起来不像家长
I think that is Melissa...
Melissa Ampton. She's an alumni.
我想这是梅丽莎...
梅丽莎・安普顿 她是个校友
Was Bilitis informed?
比莉婷丝叫过来？
- Naturally!
- Bilitis!
- 自然
- 比莉婷丝！
She's coming!
她来了！
That's my mother.
This will not be a friendly day.
那个是我妈妈 今天会不好过
It doesn't make a difference to me.
对我来说没什么不同
I heard the nicest young men around
wanted to marry her.
我听说最棒的小伙子们都想娶她
But she chose someone who nobody knew.
但她选择了某个谁也不认识的人
My sister told me.
我姐姐告诉我
They were good friends.
她们是好朋友
- Hello.
- 你好
I am Melissa Ampton Demarne,
Demarne is my married name.
我是梅丽莎・安普顿・迪马尼
迪马尼是我的夫姓
- This is my husband.
- Hello.
- 这是我丈夫
- 你好
I never recognised you.
Lovely, isn't she, Pierre?
我都认不出你了 她真可爱 是不是 皮埃尔？
Charming...
迷人...
But... I detest uniforms.
但是我讨厌制服
- Bilitis, we have to get ready, come!
- Excuse me.
- 比莉婷丝 我们得准备了 快来！
- 失陪
Did you have to offend her?
你非得冒犯她吗？
But, no.
不
Well, I wish you much
pleasure on that one.
我希望你高高兴兴面对这事
- Bilitis, it's up to you.
- I'm scared.
- 比莉婷丝 看你的了
- 我好怕
- He is there.
- Who?
- 他在那
- 谁？
The photographer.
摄影师
Excellent, wasn't it?
好极了 不是吗？
Remarkable.
不平常
They have trained for a month.
她们已经练了一个月
They chose everything themselves.
样样都是她们自己选的
They chose their own music,
made the costumes, everything.
她们选自己的音乐 做服装 一切
Is that so?
是这样吗？
Bilitis is up next.
比莉婷丝接下来上台
Go on, Bilitis.
去 比莉婷丝
- Go ahead now!
- I'm not ready!
- 现在去！
- 我没有准备好
Go on now!
现在去！
Go, go now!
The night is so deep...
夜如此深...
That it creeps between my eyelids...
爬入我的眼帘...
You will never find the path.
你将绝找不到路
You'll be lost within the wo...
你将迷失在...
Excuse me. I can't do this.
抱歉 我不能做这个
It's nothing...
没什么...
- ... just youth.
- It will improve with age.
- ...只是年轻
- 会随着年龄改善的
No, no, no sir!
Be on your way!
不不不 先生！走你自己的路
Madam, I beg of you...
女士 我求你...
- Listen to me!
- No!
- 听我说！
- 不！
I am not who you think.
我不是你以为的人
- Who are you then?
- I am Frandor.
- 那么你是谁？
- 我是弗兰多
The son of an Earl! Oh...
伯爵之子！哦...
- Feeling better?
- But what happened?
- 感觉好点吗？
- 但出什么事了？
- Nothing, nothing, stage fright.
- Stage fright?
- 没什么 没什么 怯场
- 怯场？
Leave me alone, Sabine!
别烦我 萨宾！
I'm leaving now.
我现在要走了
I know.
我知道
I will miss you.
我会想念你
I am Lucas.
我是卢卡斯
There! We're ready to leave.
好了！我们准备离开
Once my wife is ready
to leave these ladies...
一旦我妻子准备好跟这些女士告辞...
Come to the front, it's cold.
前面来 很冷
This is nanny. She knew you
when you were very young.
这是阿婆 你很小的时候她就认识你了
She was there when I was born.
She never leaves me.
我一出生她就在 她从没离开过我
She wasn't there when I was born.
我出生的时候她没在
She didn't know me when I was little.
我小的时候她不认识我
What a handicap.
真是不利条件
She mustn't weigh much more than she
did ten years ago, but she's bigger now.
她一定没比她十年前重很多 但她现在更大了
I'll give her a kiss and call her "Jij".
Okay?
我给她一个吻叫她“乖乖”好吗？
Okay. You give me a kiss and call me Jij.
好 您给我一个吻叫我“乖乖”
I used to spend all my holidays
in this room.
我过去在这房间度过我整个假期
When I was a young girl.
当我是小姑娘的时候
Do you like it?
你喜欢它吗？
Yes...
喜欢...
... provided I'm not locked up.
倘若我不被锁起来
Why would we do that?
为什么我们要那样做？
Come.
来
Bilitis...
比莉婷丝...
... your poem, what was it about?
你的诗 是关于什么的？
About?
关于？
Love?
爱？
Yes, a girl who...
是的 一个女孩她...
Do you learn to ride horses
at your school?
你在学校学会骑马了吗？
Yes, some do, but not me.
有人会了 但我没有
Why, is there a reason?
为什么 有原因吗？
No, I don't know why I don't.
不 我不知道为什么我没学会
Strange. Most girls enjoy riding.
奇怪 多数姑娘喜欢骑马
- They find it exciting.
- Pierre!
- 她们发现它好刺激
- 皮埃尔！
- Not hungry?
- No, thank you.
- 不饿？
- 不饿 谢谢
You could do with a little fattening up...
你可以丰满一点...
Don't you agree, Melissa,
that she should...?
你不赞成吗 梅丽莎 她应该...？
No...?
不？
- I am tired, excuse me.
- Would you like a little nightcap?
- 我困了 失陪
- 你想喝点睡前饮料吗？
- I'd like a large glass of milk.
- I'll come with you.
- 我想喝一大杯牛奶
- 我陪你去
Excuse me.
失陪
A glass of milk.
一杯牛奶
Why not a teddy bear?
为什么不是一个泰迪熊？
He was teasing you, you know.
He does that frequently...
他在戏弄你 你知道吗 他经常如此...
Too frequently.
太经常了
- He loves horses, doesn't he?
- Oh, it's his passion.
- 他爱马 是不是？
- 他爱马如命
He's happy around them.
He's mostly at the riding school.
他在它们身边很快乐 他大多数时间在骑校
- Do you live here all year round?
- Yes...
- 你一年到头住在这里？
- 对...
Since Pierre bought the riding school.
自从皮埃尔买下了骑校
- Do you sleep in the same bed?
- Of course.
- 你们睡一张床吗？
- 当然
What a question!
Sleep well.
提的什么问题！好好睡
What are you looking at?
你在看什么？
At you, darling.
When you were Bilitis' age.
看你 亲爱的
当你在比莉婷丝那么大时
You look like her.
你看起来就像她
I don't think so.
我想不是
Say...
我说...
What's she doing now?
她现在在干什么？
- She certainly likes her milk...
- She is very tired.
- 她当然在享受她的牛奶...
- 她非常困
She will sleep, and so will I.
她会睡觉 我也想睡觉
Pardon me,
对不起
I'm not tired.
我不困
I undressed to climb a tree,
我脱掉衣服爬树
My naked thighs embraced
the smooth and moist bark.
我的裸大腿拥抱着顺滑湿润的树皮
My sandals climbed upon the branches.
我的凉鞋踩上树枝
High up, but still beneath the leaves
and shaded from the heat,
高高的 但仍然在挡住炎热的树叶荫凉下
I straddled a wide-spread fork...
我跨在宽展的树杈上...
and swung my feet into the void.
我的脚在空中摇摆
It had rained... Drops of water
fell and flowed down my skin.
下过雨...落下的水滴顺我的皮肤流下
My hands were soiled with moss
我的手满是苔藓
and my heels were reddened
by the crushed blossoms.
我的脚跟被踩到的花染红了
I felt the lovely tree living,
when the wind passed through it,
我觉得可爱的树活了起来 当风吹过它的时候
so I locked my legs tighter,
所以我把我的腿夹得更紧
and squeezed my open lips to
the hairy nape of a bough.
张开唇紧紧咬住一根粗壮的大树枝
- Good morning, Nanny.
- Well, you're up already?
- 早上好 阿婆
- 你已经起床了？
Yes, and the rest?
是的 其他人呢？
Pierre left early this morning.
You won't see him until tonight.
皮埃尔早早离开了 你到晚上才会见到他
- And Melissa?
- She's taking a bath.
- 梅丽莎呢？
- 她在洗澡
There she is.
她来了
- Good morning, Bilitis.
- Good morning.
- 早上好 比莉婷丝
- 早上好
So you've taken a bath?
你已经洗了澡？
- Yes, and you?
- I didn't need to.
- 是的 你呢？
- 我不需要
Is it true that your husband
won't be back until tonight?
是真的吗 你丈夫直到今晚才回来？
You can call him Pierre.
Yes, he won't be here.
你可以叫他皮埃尔 是的 他不会在这
That's good.
这样很好
Now nobody can bother us.
没人能打扰我们
What do you have on?
你穿着什么？
You will put on a bathing suit.
你要穿泳衣
What are you waiting for?
你还等什么？
- Is it that bad?
- It's awful.
- 它有这么差吗？
- 它很差
I will lend you one of mine.
我借你一件我的
- On me, it'll still be dreadful.
- Don't be silly, come!
- 对我来说仍然会很差
- 别傻了 来！
Do you have a sister?
你有姐妹吗？
No.
没有
I wish I had one.
我希望我有
Come, you can't stay like that.
来 你不能像这样傻呆着
The bathing suit is made of wool,
it will never dry.
泳衣是羊毛做的 很难干
I'm used to it, you know.
我习惯了 你知道吗
That's no reason.
You'll catch a cold.
毫无道理 你会感冒的
Take it off.
脱掉它
Take it off, there's nobody here.
脱掉它 这里没人
- You are here...
- But, Bilitis...
- 这里有你...
- 但是 比莉婷丝...
You could at least help me.
你至少能帮我个忙
I am horrible.
I look like a boy. So flat.
我好恐怖 我看起来像男孩 这么平
I like you just the way you are.
我就喜欢你的样子
In school, when then I was your age...
在学校 当我在你的年纪时...
In the dormitory,
where the others slept...
在宿舍 别人睡着的时候...
You hurt me.
你弄疼了我
Does your husband do that to you?
你丈夫这么待你吗？
Stand up!
站起来！
Listen, stop spying on me, you hear?
听着 停止偷窥我 你听见了吗？
- Bilitis...
- Yes?
- 比莉婷丝...
- 哎？
If you have nothing to do tomorrow,
come to the riding school for a lesson.
如果你明天没什么事 来骑校上次课
No thanks, I don't like horses.
不 谢了 我不喜欢马
I'm afraid of them.
我怕它们
Good, I will go to sleep. Won't you?
好了 我睡觉了 你们不睡？
You forgot your book.
你忘了你的书
A book about love.
一本关于爱的书
They no longer love each other
and then they start over.
他们不再爱彼此 然后他们重新开始
Goodnight.
晚安
Ungrateful age...
不领情的年龄...
The beautiful age.
美丽的年龄
Check.
将军
How did they get to
know each other, Nanny?
他们怎么相互认识的 阿婆？
At a riding school.
He gave lessons there.
在一家骑校 他在那授课
Did she really fall in love with him?
她真的爱上了他吗？
First with the horse, then him afterwards.
首先爱上了马 然后爱上了他
I think she made a mistake.
I would have chosen the horse.
我想她错了 要是我会选马
Yes. That's something you can't say.
对 有些事你没法说
To who, the horse, or Melissa?
对谁 对马 还是对梅丽莎？
Both, you best keep quiet.
都对 你最好安静
All the same...
全都一样...
If she was really unhappy...
如果她之前真的不快乐...
she wouldn't be so beautiful as she is.
她不会像这样美
Dearest Lucas...
最亲爱的卢卡斯...
No! Not this way! No!
不！不要这样！不！
I don't want to...
我不想...
Just two minutes!
- 比莉婷丝
- 就两分钟！
Take your time.
慢慢洗
Are we going to the beach today?
我们今天去海滩吗？
I don't think so.
我想不去
Why aren't we?
为什么我们不去？
I would love to go.
我好想去
You're going. I'm not.
你去 我不去
- Why would I go alone?
- You'll see.
- 为什么我要一个人去？
- 你会明白的
Your husband's a brute!
你丈夫是个畜生！
I told you not to spy on me.
我告诉你了不要偷窥我
It's this house, you can hear everything.
是这房子的问题 你能听见一切
Once more, Bilitis,
it's my business, not yours.
再说一次 比莉婷丝
这是我的事 不是你的事
And why do you leave me by myself?
为什么你丢下我一个人？
With your friend you're not alone.
有你的朋友你不是一个人
Which friend?
哪个朋友？
Your boyfriend.
你的男朋友
Which boyfriend?
哪个男朋友？
Dear Lucas. Now, you don't have
to write anything in your letter.
亲爱的卢卡斯
你不必把什么都写进你的信
- Lucas?
- That's what I said.
- 卢卡斯？
- 我就是这么说的
Who's spying on who?
谁在偷窥谁？
Why are you doing this?
为什么你这样做？
So that you wouldn't
imagine that you are in love.
好让你不幻想你在恋爱
To lose the illusion, to
get a little experience.
失去幻想 长点经验
I still don't get it.
我仍然搞不懂
I just know that nothing changes.
我就知道没什么改变
- You want ice cream?
- Yes.
- 你想吃冰淇淋吗？
- 好
Come. The girl wants ice cream.
这女孩想要冰淇淋
Pistachio, vanilla, chocolate?
阿月浑子果、香草、巧克力？
- All.
- 全要
- Serve yourself.
- Yes? - Yes.
- 自己拿
- 行吗？ - 行
If I understand you...
如果我理解你的意思...
you cannot go out tonight...
你今天不能出去
not tomorrow and not
the day after tomorrow.
明天不行 后天也不行
Absolutely not.
绝对不行
Why?
为什么？
Melissa won't allow it.
梅丽莎不会允许
Melissa...?
梅丽莎？
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
- 你确定？
- 是的
- You could climb out the window.
- Melissa wouldn't like that.
- 你可以爬出窗户
- 梅丽莎不会喜欢
- Now, Bilitis, I'm serious.
- So am I.
- 比莉婷丝 我是认真的
- 我也是
- That's good!
- I work during the day...
- 好好吃！
- 我白天工作...
and you can't go out at night...
你不能在晚上出去...
That's like the watchman and his wife.
One wonders when would they have children.
这就像巡夜者和他妻子
令人纳闷他们什么时候有孩子
Do you think of having children?
你想有孩子？
Wipe your chin.
擦你的下巴
Good. I don't go to work.
好 我不去工作
We meet each other during the day.
我们在白天彼此见面
You'll come by bicycle.
你要骑单车来
Do I have a bicycle?
我有单车吗？
The bicycle that you'll get from Melissa.
你可以从梅丽莎那里借单车
Why must I ask Melissa for a bicycle?
为什么我必须向梅丽莎借单车？
Bilitis, do you want us to meet?
比莉婷丝 你想要我们见面吧？
Yes.
是的
No. I might want to see you
不 我可能想见你
so I'll come by the bicycle
that I'll ask Melissa for.
那么我借梅丽莎的单车骑过来
And... other days you ride your
motor bike to the house.
改天你开你的摩托来这房子
- You have a motor bike?
- Yes.
- 你有辆摩托车吧？
- 是的
Agreed? I come some days
and you come the other days, agreed?
同意吗？我来几天你来几天 同意吗？
Agreed.
同意
- Kiss me for the effort.
- No.
- 我赢了吻我
- 不
This way then.
A kiss, quickly!
那么这样 快亲一个！
There!
好了！
You've been kissed.
你已经被吻了
- Watch the ducks!
- Quack, quack! The ducks!
- 小心鸭子！
- 呱呱 鸭子！
- That's Melissa's husband.
- I've seen him at your school.
- 那是梅丽莎的丈夫
- 我在你的学校已经见过他了
- Did he spend a lot to set this place up?
- It was all paid for by Melissa's father.
- 他建起这地方花了很多钱？
- 都是梅丽莎的父亲付的账
He's a good looking man.
他是个好看的男人
He's not my type.
他不合我的口味
I sure hope not.
我肯定希望不合
Should I try to ride in Monte Carlo?
我应该尝试去蒙特卡洛比赛吗？
Yes, not bad, but Monte Carlo is
rather difficult, you know.
是的 不坏 但蒙特卡洛相当难 你知道吗
Yes, but if I have my teacher
who gives me confidence.
是的 但我有老师给我信心
Moral support, I see.
精神支持 我明白
Are you going to Monte Carlo?
你会去蒙特卡洛吗？
Not that I know.
我哪里知道
They will see us,
still I might as well say hello.
他们会看到我们 我还是去打声招呼
You look overjoyed.
你看起来大喜
Do I go, or do I not?
我去 还是不去？
Maybe not... look.
也许不去...看
See you tomorrow, on your bike.
明天见 骑你的单车来
- Yes.
- What bicycle?
- 好
- 什么单车？
Wait!
等等！
You didn't say goodbye.
你没有说再见
Look, Melissa, what do I say?
看 梅丽莎 我要说什么？
Nothing. You've never met.
不用说什么 你们从未结识
Good day, Madam.
日安 夫人
A strange manner to drink coffee together.
一起喝咖啡的奇怪方式
Please sit down.
请坐下
I'm going I have to get
the horses ready tonight.
我要走了 我今晚要准备好马
Three days of hanging around
for a chance to win a medal.
闲逛三天为了有机会赢得奖牌
I find it an awful bore.
我发现它相当无聊
But if I don't go to the games...
但如果我不去比赛...
You don't need me to
make up your mind for you.
你不需要我为你下决心
Isn't it in Monte Carlo, your show?
你要去的比赛是不是在蒙特卡洛？
Yes, how did you know that?
是的 你怎么知道的？
I read the newspaper, you know.
我读了报纸 你知道吗
Are you going to take us, Melissa and me?
你会带我们去？梅丽莎和我？
Melissa, do you want to come along?
梅丽莎 你想一起来吗？
Not as much as you like to have me there.
不如你想要我去那么想
Why are you spinning like that?
为什么你这样转来转去？
She wants to ask you a question.
她想问你个问题
She's waiting until I'm gone.
Is that right?
她正等着我走 不是吗？
Yes.
是的
Goodnight.
晚安
You know, this way you
don't have to drive me.
你知道吗 这样你不必开车送我
What way?
怎样？
- If I had a bicycle.
- Is that all?
- 如果我有了单车
- 就这个？
He's wonderful, Melissa, he's so nice...
他棒极了 梅丽莎 他人好好...
Say no more...
you'll have a bicycle.
别再说了 你会有单车的
Thank you!
谢谢！
You use your tongue,
你用你的舌头
like this, to say thank you?
像这样 来说谢谢你？
Just with you.
只是跟你
I can't keep up!
我不能继续了！
That is normal, I'm a man.
很正常 我是个男人
It's easy for you, you have a motor bike.
你当然容易 你有摩托车
This is not so easy.
You don't have one.
这不容易 你没有过不知道
- Take my picture.
- I have no camera.
- 给我拍照
- 我没带相机
Yes, take my picture.
给我拍照
- Okay.
- This way!
- 好
- 这样！
You know, Melissa is really wonderful.
你知道吗 梅丽莎真的很棒
But she doesn't want me to talk about you.
但她不想要我跟你说话
Really?
真的？
That makes it difficult,
because I only want to talk about you.
让我好难办 因为我只想跟你说话
- You don't want to?
- Not this way.
- 你不想？
- 不想这样
- How?
- I think...
- 怎样？
- 我想...
... softly.
...温柔的
That was my first time.
这是我的第一次
No, not here!
不 这儿不要！
Not here, not now, not this evening!
You make me crazy!
这儿不要 现在不要 今晚不要！
你让我要疯了！
I'll see if Bilitis is asleep.
Close the windows and shutters.
我去看比莉婷丝睡了吗 关好窗户
- Why?
- She hears us!
- 为什么？
- 她听到我们了！
She's a pest!
她真讨厌！
Bilitis.
比莉婷丝
I don't think I know how to kiss.
我想我不知道怎么亲吻
What do you do after you
stick out your tongue?
你伸出你的舌头后怎么做？
You'll learn.
你会学到的
- Teach me.
- No.
- 教我
- 不
- Please.
- Some other time.
- 拜托
- 改天
No, he will take me for a child.
不 他会把我当小孩子
- Come on.
- No.
- 快点
- 不
- Come on.
- No.
- 快点
- 不
- This way?
- Yes.
- 这样？
- 是的
Am I doing this right?
我这样做对吗？
Melissa, what are you doing up there?
梅丽莎 你在上面干什么？
- He becomes impatient.
- Yes.
- 他变得不耐烦了
- 对
- He's going to make love to you?
- Yes.
- 他会跟你做爱？
- 对
Can I reach you in Monte Carlo?
我能去蒙特卡洛找你吗？
Why?
为什么？
To tell me that you
can't sleep without me?
告诉我没有我你睡不着？
Don't forget the blue chamber.
别忘了蓝房间
The blue chamber?
蓝房间？
Yes, he slept there.
对 他在那儿睡的
I wasn't feeling well.
我当时不太舒服
Exactly the day before I leave.
What a coincidence!
正好在我离开前一天 真巧！
I learned a lot of things about him.
我学到了关于他的很多情况
What?
什么情况？
What a man is, for example...
举例说 一个男人多么...
Not encouraging.
让人没有希望
You can rest for three
days and nights without me.
没有我你能休息三天三夜
When I think what he's
going to do in Monte Carlo.
当我想他去蒙特卡洛干什么时
I can't tell you, Nanny.
我不能告诉你 阿婆
Good, I can go.
好 我可以走了
You seem sad that he's gone.
你看起来很悲伤他走了
It's not as simple as that.
You'll understand later.
不是这么简单 你以后会懂的
Never mind.
Are you going somewhere?
别管了 你要去哪里吗？
Now I feel bad if I leave you alone.
我丢下你一个人让我感觉很糟
You're going to anyway.
Lucas?
你总之要走的 去找卢卡斯？
Have you done anything yet?
你已经做了什么事了？
Of course not.
当然没有
That's good.
You have plenty of time for that.
这就好 你有大量时间做那事
Men aren't all like Pierre.
男人不都像皮埃尔
There are some that are
gentle, kind, and nice.
有些男人温柔 善良 体贴
Lucas, perhaps?
卢卡斯 也许？
Yesterday you were lively.
What's wrong?
昨天你好有活力 怎么了？
Must I jump for joy because you
told me all Melissa's troubles?
我必须欢呼雀跃吗
因为你告诉了我梅丽莎所有的麻烦？
You were in a bad mood when I
arrived even before I said anything.
我一来你就情绪不好
甚至在我没说什么之前
I wasn't in a bad mood, only sad.
我没有情绪不好 只是伤心
Just today when I want to be cheered up.
就在今天我想开心的时候
What do you want?
A person can't be funny everyday.
你想怎样？一个人不可能天天谈笑风生
You get on my nerves.
你让我生气
I lived with a girl that I just
left because of you.
我之前跟一个姑娘住 我就是因为你离开了
That is normal...
这很正常...
That's extraordinary! Normal!
这很不平常！正常！
I'm not very happy!
我不是非常快乐！
- You regret it.
- I don't regret it!
- 你后悔了
- 我不后悔！
Is that your boyfriend, the photographer?
这是你的男朋友 摄影师？
That's none of your business.
不关你的事
Your boyfriend and your
problems are none of my business.
你的男朋友和你的烦恼都不关我的事
And I'm not going alone to Monte Carlo.
但我不是一个人去蒙特卡洛
That's none of your business, okay?
这也不关你的事 好吗？
I believe we understand each other.
Good day.
我相信我们彼此理解 日安
I was hoping you would return.
我正希望你回来
Was that Melissa's husband?
那是梅丽莎的丈夫？
Take me away somewhere please.
请带我走
- What happened?
- Nothing. Take me away.
- 怎么了？
- 没什么 带我走
Wait.
等等
You're like all the girls.
Let me finish!
你就像所有女孩一样 让我说完！
You always try to make me feel remorseful.
你总是想让我感觉懊悔
You feel remorseful?
你感觉懊悔？
Sometimes, you deserve a beating!
有时 你欠打！
Go ahead, then.
那么打吧！
- Bilitis, I'm warning you!
- What are you waiting for?
- 比莉婷丝 我警告你！
- 你还等什么？
Enough! Just stop!
够了！别来了！
You're driving me crazy.
你要让我疯了
You're impossible.
你让人没法忍受
Then you must beat me.
那你就打我
Kiss me.
吻我
- Never.
- Yes.
- 绝不
- 要
- No.
- Yes.
- 不
- 要
- No.
- Yes...
- 不
- 要...
No...
不...
You're not going to make love to me?
你不会是要跟我做爱吧？
One does not die from it.
做了又不会死
Yes, but I have never...
是的 但我从没有...
- I've done nothing.
- You call that "nothing".
- 我什么也没做
- 你说“什么也没做”？
Almost nothing.
几乎什么也没做
Bilitis... listen.
比莉婷丝 听我说
Listen. It's natural for
a girl and a boy...
一个女人和一个男人做很自然...
If the girl wants the boy, it's normal.
如果这女人想要这男人 很正常
Otherwise he'll look at other girls.
否则他会找别的女人
Do that, go look!
It makes no difference to me!
你去找找看！对我来说没什么不同！
- It can't make a difference.
- What is it?
- 不可能有所不同
- 怎么了？
What is it with her?
她怎么了？
A virgin... huh!
处女...哼！
Melissa!
梅丽莎！
Come here...
过来...
I hate men.
我讨厌男人
You mustn't.
你才不
You're like me.
你就像我
- We're made the same.
- Be silent.
- 我们一副德性
- 安静
You can't hurt me.
I'm happy with you.
你不可能伤害我 我跟你在一起很快乐
You're crazy.
你疯了
I am Pierre.
我是皮埃尔
Alas, when I think of her,
my throat becomes dry.
唉 我一想她 我就喉咙发干
My head bows down.
我俯首垂眉
My breasts harden and ache.
我的胸变硬 疼痛
I shudder and weep as I walk.
我边走边发抖哭泣
When I see her, my heart stops.
我看见她时我的心停止跳动
My hands tremble, my feet turn cold,
my cheeks burn fiery red...
我的手颤抖 我的脚冰凉
我的脸颊绯红滚烫...
my temples throbbing.
我的太阳穴跳动
When I touch her, I go mad.
我触碰她时 我疯了
My arms stiffen, my knees are weak.
我的胳膊僵硬 我的膝盖发软
I fall before her and lie waiting
as if a death could take me.
我倒在她面前躺着等待
仿佛死神可以带走我
Her every word is a wound to me.
她的每个词对我来说是伤口
Her love is a torture to me.
她的爱对我来说是折磨
Strangers passing hear me crying.
经过的陌生人听到我的哭
Alas...
唉...
How may I call on my own beloved?
我如何可以拜访我的心上人？
What do you think?
你怎么想的？
Listen. It was strange,
it was gentle, it was beautiful.
听着 它很奇异 它很温柔 它很美丽
But it could never happen again.
但它绝不可能再发生
- Never again?
- No, never.
- 绝不可能再次？
- 对 绝不可能
Okay, you find that you don't. I find...
好吧 你发现你不可能 我发现...
Nothing. As if it had never happened.
不可能 就当它从没发生过
You don't need me any more.
你不再需要我了
You again!
又是你！
I haven't been nice to Bilitis.
So I thought I'd like to see her.
我对比莉婷丝不好 所以我想见见她
Even if you love me more than anyone...
即使你爱我甚于别人...
you would still need a man.
你仍然需要个男人
Where are you going?
你去哪儿？
- To find you one.
- What?
- 给你找一个
- 什么？
- A man.
- You're crazy.
- 一个男人
- 你疯了
You only love me when I am.
你只爱疯了时的我
If anybody calls for me, I'm not here.
如果有谁找我 说我不在
She's impossible.
她很难追
- Where is she going?
- To get me a present.
- 她去哪？
- 去给我找一件礼物
- It's so urgent... that she hurries?
- She thinks so.
- 很紧急吗...让她这么匆匆？
- 她觉得是的
You didn't handle her very well.
你没有很好对待她
You shouldn't have.
你本不该的
Not like that.
不该那样
Not right away.
不该马上
I came to apologise.
我来道歉
She ran away.
她跑开了
Excuse me.
原谅我
- Hello!
- Hello.
- 你好！
- 你好
- Well, maybe you'll do.
- That would surprise me.
- 也许你会做
- 我好吃惊
- Let me explain.
- Just leave.
- 让我解释
- 只管离开
I'm not available.
You're wasting your time.
得不到我的 你在浪费你的时间
What will you have?
你要什么？
A glass of milk.
一杯牛奶
- Do you always act like this?
- Like what?
- 你总是像这样吗？
- 像什么？
- You're nice.
- Me, nice?
- 你可爱
- 我 可爱？
- The same.
- I said I wanted milk.
- 来一样的
- 我说了我想要牛奶
A strange way to meet boys.
约男孩子的奇怪方式
Oh yes?
哦 是吗？
Which games do you play?
你在玩什么游戏？
Let's just forget it.
让我们忘了它
You could go,
or you could come and sit.
你可以走人 或者你可以来坐下
I've been watching you.
我一直在观察你
The first when you look... zero.
你初看起来...一无可取
The second... still zero.
再看起来...还是一无可取
You'll never succeed.
你绝不会成功
I always get what I want.
我总是得到我想要的
Come.
来
- What is it?
- The same as mine...
- 是什么？
- 和我一样的
You don't know what you want.
你不知道你想要什么
That I know. A lover.
我知道 一个情人
Not for me. For a friend.
不是为我 为一个朋友
- To do this... for her.
- For her, nice.
- 去做...为了她
- 为了她 可爱
A man who's handsome,
and gentle, and strong.
一个英俊的 温柔的 强壮的男人
Who won't ask questions
and goes away afterwards.
不问问题 事后走开的男人
And who you find attractive also.
你也觉得有吸引力的男人
Naturally.
自然
She knows what you're looking for.
You should've brought her along.
她知道你该找什么 你本该带她一起来
Melissa.
梅丽莎
That's her name?
这是她的名字？
Melissa... pick up a man on the street?
梅丽莎 在街上捡一个男人？
Impossible!
不可能！
- I like you.
- You'll like Melissa even more.
- 我喜欢你
- 你会甚至更喜欢梅丽莎
Perhaps... but what you want
is out of the question.
也许 但你想要的是不可能的
Why?
为什么？
Because...
因为...
Wait... you're right.
等等 你说的没错
Only she can know.
只有她能知道
Only she can choose.
只有她能选择
But, I have no money.
但是我没有钱
How much do you need?
你需要多少？
Listen, if a person fights with
someone for some reason,
听着 如果一个人因为某原因跟某人吵了一架
could she speak to him...
她能跟他说话...
without going back on the first reason?
而不重提一开始的吵架原因吗？
Do you want money or not?
你想要钱还是不想？
No, he owes me at least that much.
不 他至少欠我那么多
Excuse me!
失陪！
My name is Nikias.
You can find me at my boat.
我叫尼基阿斯 你能在我的船上找到我
Well, well...
好 好...
No...
不...
I'm not coming to see you.
我不会来找你
I've decided not to speak to you.
我已经决定了不跟你说话
So I won't speak to you.
所以我不会跟你说话
But... you are Mr. Lucas Mercier,
photographer, right?
但是...你是卢卡斯・梅西耶先生
摄影师 对吧？
Yes, that's me.
Welcome!
对 是我 欢迎！
That...
那个...
and that one...
还有那个...
- And that.
- Yes.
- 还有那个
- 好
That...
那个...
and this one.
和这个
Thank you!
谢谢你！
Hello, Lucas.
你好 卢卡斯
Oh... Mister.
哦 先生
Take him.
拍他
Nikias!
尼基阿斯！
Sorry... it was a task.
抱歉...完成任务
And him, why not take him?
还有他 为什么不拍他？
Do you know each other?
你们相互认识？
Yes.
是的
Why me?
为什么说我？
No importance. Any left?
不重要 还有胶卷剩吗？
I have to reload.
我得再装
- ... or do you have enough?
- How many do you have?
- 或者你找够了？
- 你拍了多少？
That's good.
I guess 50% rejections...
好吧 我猜要剔除一半
I never miss a photo.
我拍照从不失手
No, not the photos...
some of the places are wrong.
不 不是照片的事...是地方不够
Oh... the places.
哦 地方的事
I didn't hire you to make comments,
only photos, that's it!
我不是雇你来评论的 是来照相的 就这样！
Very good.
非常好
- Do you do want an envelope?
- How much do I owe you?
- 你想要个信封吗？
- 我欠你多少？
One kiss.
一个吻
I already paid. Greetings.
我已经付了 再见
10, 11, 12
10 11 12
13, 14
13 14
- Don't you like any of them?
- No.
- 他们中有你喜欢的吗？
- 没有
15, 16...
15 16...
I'm afraid your photographer went
through all this trouble for nothing.
我恐怕你的摄影师白辛苦了一场
What about the photographer, himself?
摄影师他自己怎么样？
I might not say no to him!
我不可能对他说不！
- No really?
- You seem hesitant.
- 真的？
- 你看起来好犹豫
No... that's not it...
不...不是的...
You don't want me to be happy?
你不想要我快乐吗？
- Yes I do!
- Let's continue...
- 我想！
- 让我们继续看...
17... 18
17...18
19...
That's my friend, Nikias.
这是我朋友 尼基阿斯
Nikias...?
尼基阿斯？
Even if you like him, you can't have him.
就算你喜欢他 你也不能拥有他
- I don't think anyone can.
- Pity.
- 我觉得谁也不能
- 可惜
When I try to imagine you with a man,
it's always a different man...
当我想像你跟一个男人时
他总是一个不同的男人...
and each time, I can't bear it.
每次 我都受不了
With Pierre... it's terrible.
跟皮埃尔...又太恐怖了
I should never have let you love me.
我本来绝不该让你爱我
I would've loved you anyway.
反正我已经爱上你了
Maybe some I love, it will be different.
也许找个我爱的男人 就不同了
For me and for you.
为了我 为了你
- I will persuade him.
- Lucas?
- 我会劝他
- 卢卡斯？
Of course not, Nikias.
当然不是 尼基阿斯
- You said, "With someone you love..."
- I don't love Lucas.
- 你说找个你爱的男人
- 我不爱卢卡斯
Not any more.
再也不爱
It's as if I never loved him.
就当我从没爱过他
Can I invite Nikias here?
我能邀请尼基阿斯来吗？
But you said to me,
he might not accept.
但你跟我说 他可能不会接受
I can try.
我可以试试
- It's important to her, Nikias.
- I don't know her.
- 这对她很重要 尼基阿斯
- 我不认识她
And it's also important to me.
这对我也很重要
You did hear me.
你听到我的话了
Yes, but, I'm only asking
you to come and see her.
是的 但是我只求你来见见她
We invited some friends and
you could bring some too!
我们邀请了一些朋友 你也可以带来一些！
You said you like me, prove it then.
你说你喜欢我 那么证明
- You'll regret it.
- Yes...
- 你会后悔的
- 答应吧...
Agreed.
好吧
- Are you crazy?
- Yes, I'm crazy.
- 你疯了吗？
- 对 我疯了
You're crazy, Bilitis.
你疯了 比莉婷丝
I know. People are always
saying that. Look...
我知道 人们总是这样说 看...
Look...
看...
- Perhaps these?
- No.
- 也许这件？
- 不
No.
不
Perhaps these? For you.
也许这件？
给你
- For me?
- Perhaps...
- 给我？
- 也许...
Very well... these are for me!
非常好 这件给我！
And these are perfect for you.
I know how to do your hair.
这件对你很完美 我知道怎么做你的头发
It's ridiculous asking all these
friends over at such short notice.
太荒唐了 请所有朋友过来
预先通知时间这么短
Why? We invite them, they accepted.
为什么？我们邀请他们 他们接受了
Nikias will probably bring
some people over too.
尼基阿斯也可能会带几个人过来
We could've postponed it until tomorrow.
我们本可以延迟到明天
That's too far away, Melissa...
I couldn't wait that long.
明天太遥远 梅丽莎...我不能等那么久
I thought this was for me.
我想这是为了我
It is for you.
是为了你
I want you to be beautiful.
我想要你美丽
Absolutely beautiful.
绝对美丽
If I was Pierre, I know what I'd do...
with the riding school
如果我是皮埃尔 我知道我会怎么...
管好骑校
Pierre is not here?
皮埃尔不在这？
Monte Carlo, for the game.
蒙特卡洛 去比赛
Melissa is adorable.
梅丽莎真迷人
The champagne is delicious.
香槟真美味
But what are we doing here?
但我们在这干什么？
Isn't she beautiful?
难道她不美吗？
I've bathed, dressed,
and fixed her hair.
我帮她洗澡 换衣服 做她的头发
If I could love her...
如果要我爱她...
I'd have to get rid of you first.
我不得不首先除掉你
In what way?
怎么除掉？
Kill you.
杀了你
Can I show you the park?
我能带你去看庭院吗？
Can I throw everyone here out?
我能把这里每个人扔出去吗？
You know why you're here?
你知道为什么你来吧？
Hasn't Bilitis told you that
I'm never somewhere entirely?
比莉婷丝没告诉你我才不想来吗？
Bilitis always exaggerates.
比莉婷丝总是吹牛皮
Bilitis doesn't know what to expect of me.
比莉婷丝不知道我期待什么
She thinks she knows.
That's different.
她以为她知道 其实不同
When I arrived, you were dancing.
我到达时 你正在跳舞
I was all alone.
我当时好孤单
And are you now?
你现在呢？
Who is to decide? You? Me?
谁将决定呢？你？我？
Nobody can decide about that.
没人能决定那个
No, it's not possible.
不 它不可能
You know it, and I know it.
你知道 我知道
That's true...
这话是真的...
and not true.
又不是真的
Come!
来！
Pity about Nikias...
可惜尼基阿斯...
You know...
你知道吗...
He doesn't belong with us.
他不属于我们
In fact he belongs to nobody.
事实上他不属于任何女人
You look so alone and far away.
你看来如此孤单和遥远
Melissa, embrace me.
梅丽莎 拥抱我
You were to find me a man!
你要给我找个男人！
Come dance with me.
来跟我跳舞
Suppose I asked you to come to my room.
要是我请你来我房间呢
That's foolish. I know you...
不好吧 我知道你...
And I know myself.
而且我知道我自己
Not him.
不要是他
No.
对
It's true...
I would've had...
说真的...我应该...
Do something, Nikias...
做点什么 尼基阿斯...
It's you.
该是你
That's what you want.
这就是你想要的
I didn't invite you.
我没有邀请你
I thought it was an oversight.
我还以为是疏漏了
Don't worry about it.
别担心
Bilitis was hoping you'd come.
比莉婷丝正希望你来
Thank you.
谢谢你
Do you still hesitate?
你仍然犹豫吗？
Go on!
去！
Come...
来...
Lucas.
卢卡斯
I know.
我知道
We've already met each other.
我们已经见过彼此了
I told you, "It could be someone I love."
我告诉你了 “也许找个我爱的男人”
Let's go.
我们走
Melissa...
梅丽莎...
Ah... it's you, Nanny.
啊 是您 阿婆
What's happening here?
这里发生了什么？
What are you thinking about?
你在想什么？
Who are you thinking about?
你在想谁？
Have you noticed?
你注意到了吗？
She laughs...
她欢笑
She laughs... when she trusts you.
她欢笑 当她信任你的时候
Yes...
是的